

luishorcajomoreno@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Portfolio

ABOUT

I am a multidisciplinary designer with a unique perspective and strong problem solving skills. I aim to create a more socially engaged community by shaping digital experiences in both the cultural and commercial industries. I care about finding innovative solutions by deeply understanding the people around me and the worlds they live in.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SMARTFROG & CANARY — PRODUCT DESIGNER

April 2021 - Present

Crafting & designing the best solution for Canary users by working in a cross-functional team. Producing end-to-end holistic user experiences with a structure that ensures ease of understanding by users.

FREELANCE — UX / UI DESIGNER

June 2020 - June 2021

Working as freelance collaborating closely with product management teams to frame problems, define goals, plan and prioritize product development efforts and performing explorative user research studies by scoping, planning and conducting user interviews and contextual inquiry.

VIERNES COMUNICACIÓN — GRAPHIC DESIGNER

October 2013 - October 2014

Working as the main graphic designer within a small team of three creative directors in the communication field, social innovation and inclusivity. Improving my visual designing skills, working with deadlines and growing in a team.

ADVIRA BEYOND, KUO EXPERIENCE & TELLING INSIGHT — COOLHUNTER

January 2009 - October 2014

Providing advice and perspective as a consumer and trendsetter to marketing companies, collaborating with them to create new product research, trends and ways of consumption.

EDUCATION

IRONHACK — UX/UI DESIGN

April 2020

A 24 weeks bootcamp learning the fundamentals of User Centered Design.

SALESIANOS — GRAPHIC DESIGN

June 2015

4 years of learning the elementary principles of digital and graphic design.

LANGUAGES

TOOLS

Figma, Sketch, Invision, Principle, Adobe Creative Suite, HTML/CSS.

SKILLS

DESIGN & CORE BUSINESS

Design & innovation processes, interaction design, UX research, benchmarking & brand positioning, concept development, cross-functional teams.

SOFT

Communication - Collaboration - Synergy Excitement - Equality - Curiosity - Empathy

English Spanish